By 2026, AI could automate up to 70% of
everyday work tasks. In this video, I'm
sharing 17 new technology trends that
will shape 2026. From brain controlled
devices to walking robots and how
they're already starting to change the
way we live. Let's dive in. Number 17,
low code, no code development. You ever
feel like building an app or tool is
only for engineers? Well, as you can
already tell, that's not the case
anymore. By 2026, it's expected that
over 75% of new apps will be built using
lowode or no code platforms. That's
stuff like Glide, Bubble, and Microsoft
Power Apps where you just drag, drop,
and hit publish. Even OpenAI is letting
people build their own AI tools with
zero code using those custom GPTs. and
Google's app sheet businesses are
automating full workflows without hiring
devs. Number 16, AI crafted experience
in extended reality. VR isn't just
headsets and games anymore. It's getting
smart, like actually thinking for itself
smart. In 2026, we'll see more of these
AI powered XR or extended reality spaces
that generate themselves based on what
you're doing. Nvidia is already doing
this with real-time characters that hold
full-on conversations. Meta's pumping
billions into avatars that don't just
look better, they react, they improvise.
And at CES, virtual shops were adapting
their layout depending on how people
moved around. Number 15, smart
infrastructure and lo 2.0. All right,
let's zoom out a bit. Literally, by
2026, there will be over 30 billion IoT
devices. We're talking traffic lights
that adjust in real time based on
congestion, which is already a thing in
Singapore. Warehouses using AWS and
Verizon to track a quick inventory
without human input. And in South Korea,
they got smart poles that do everything
from air quality monitoring to charging
your phone. Number 14, privacy first AI
and local processing. Apple's new chips
can now handle AI tasks directly on your
device. No cloud, no upload, just fast
private processing. And Meta's Llama 3
models, you can run them locally, too.
Intel's Meteor Lake chips are designed
to do this out of the box with built-in
AI accelerators. With pressure building
from Europe's GDPR and California's
CCPA, AI is learning how to stay offline
and keep your data to itself. Number 13,
workflow automation at scale. Tools like
Service Now, UiPath, and Zapier are
helping companies automate full
workflows from hiring to invoicing. No
human hands needed. Service Now actually
reported up to 65% reduction in
repetitive work thanks to automation in
large companies. Amazon's warehouses
already use predictive analytics to
coordinate people and robots. So yeah,
we're not just talking about automating
tasks anymore. Whole processes are
running on their own and it's happening
fast. Number 12, AI enhanced robotics in
retail and logistics. Agility Robotics
started deploying its digital robot at
Amazon warehouses in 2024. Walmart,
they're using autonomous shelf scanners
in over a thousand stores. And if you're
on a college campus, chances are you've
seen one of those Starship or Kiwi bots
delivering food. These bots aren't
remote controlled. They're using AI
vision, realtime mapping, and they're
getting smarter every week, especially
with worker shortages. These robots are
here to stay. Number 11, AI native
operating systems. So, you know how your
phone suggests texts or autocorrects on
the fly? In 2026, that kind of AI won't
just be in apps. It's getting baked
directly into operating systems.
Microsoft's already testing C-Pilot
inside Windows 11, where you can
literally ask your desktop to summarize
files, rewrite emails, or generate
images without switching tabs. Apple's
expected to announce more AI native
features in MacOSS and iOS, too, running
on device with their new neural engines.
It's not just smarter apps anymore. It's
your entire system thinking with you
step by step. Number 10, wearables that
know you better than you do. Wearables
aren't just step counters anymore.
They're turning into 24/7 health
monitors that can track stress, blood
oxygen, and even early illness. Aura and
Whoop are already giving athletes and
everyday users recovery scores and sleep
cycles. Now, new models are adding blood
sugar tracking without finger pricks,
and companies like Mavano are working on
continuous blood pressure wearables.
Some smart rings even detect changes in
skin temperature before you get sick.
And the best part, a lot of these
devices now feed data to AI that gives
you personalized nudges, not just
numbers. Number nine, quantum computing
nears utility. Quantum computing has
always sounded like sci-fi, but 2026
might be the year it starts showing up
in real workflows. IBM hit a,000
quibbits in 2023 and plans to debut a
1386 Quibbit chip this year. They're
also developing error corrected systems
that are getting closer to doing
something useful like simulating
molecules for new drugs or optimizing
supply chains way faster than classical
computers. Companies like Google, ION Q,
and Regetti are right there in the race,
too. It's still early days, but the
demos are getting real and the pace is
quickening. Number eight, AR glasses
replace screens. We've been talking
about AR glasses for a decade, but now
they're finally closing in on actual
usefulness. Apple's Vision Pro got the
ball rolling, and now companies like
Meta, XR Real, and Samsung are working
on lightweight glasses with realtime
overlays. Things like live captions,
navigation arrows, and even translated
subtitles floating in front of you. By
2026, you might not need to pull out
your phone to reply to a text or check
directions. And with AI handling
context, these glasses could know what
info you want before you ask. Number
seven, AI and healthc care gets
personal. In 2024, Google Deep Mind
announced its AI model could detect 21
types of diseases from retinal scans,
sometimes earlier than humans could. In
the US, hospitals are starting to use AI
to analyze patient data and spot signs
of sepsis or cardiac risk hours before
symptoms show. We're also seeing AI used
in cancer treatment planning,
personalizing chemo regimens based on
your genetic makeup. Number six, Edge AI
chips everywhere. Chances are the next
phone or laptop you buy will have an AI
chip built in. In 2026, Edge AI means
realtime smarts right on your device. No
cloud, no lag. Apple's A17 Pro and M4
chips already do this, handling language
translation, image editing, and voice
recognition instantly. Qualcomm
Snapdragon X Elite is bringing that same
firepower to Windows laptops. And
Intel's Meteor Lake chips come with
MPUs, neural processing units that let
you run AI tasks with almost no power
drain. It's turning every device you own
into its own little brain. Number five,
AI powered home assistants. Smart
speakers used to just play music, but
now they're walking around. Amazon's
Astro, first introduced as a home robot
in 2021, is quietly getting smarter.
It's already being used for home patrol,
elder care, and voice command delivery
inside homes and offices. Apple's
rumored to be working on its own
tabletop robot, internally dubbed J595,
that could swivel and track users during
FaceTime calls. Meanwhile, in China,
humanoid showroom assistants are already
helping customers and handing out
brochures. These assistants are moving
past the voiceonly stage, adding
screens, wheels, arms, and in some
cases, facial expressions. Number four,
humanoid robots go commercial. We're now
at the point where humanoid robots
aren't just walking, they're working. In
2024, Figure AI signed a partnership
with BMW to bring its bipedal robot,
Figure01,
into automotive manufacturing. Agility
Robotics is deploying Digit in logistics
environments, and Tesla's Optimus is
already doing basic factory tasks like
folding laundry and sorting parts.
What's changed? These robots can now
walk, lift, and perform repetitive tasks
with just enough dexterity to be useful.
And more importantly, they're becoming
cheap enough to scale. Some models are
expected to cost less than a small car
by 2026. Number three, AI agents that
work for you. This one's moving fast. AI
agents aren't just responding to prompts
anymore. They're handling full tasks
from start to finish. Take Devon, an AI
software engineer demoed by Cognition
Labs in 2024. It can build a full
website, debug code, and deploy it live
all autonomously. Auto GPT and similar
tools can already chain tasks together,
plan an itinerary, book reservations,
and send you a summary. In companies,
these agents are being trained to
onboard employees, manage data, or
respond to clients automatically.
Instead of just chatting with AI, you're
starting to delegate to it. Number two,
generative AI becomes default. In 2026,
most of what you read, hear, or watch
will have been touched, if not created,
by generative AI. Open AAI, Google, and
Anthropic are pushing the limits of
large multimodal models like GPT5 and
Gemini Ultra, capable of handling text,
images, video, and even audio in a
single conversation. Adobe's Firefly and
Runway ML are powering commercial video
editing, while 11 Labs let you clone
voices and generate speech in seconds.
This isn't just a trend, it's a shift in
how content gets made. Whether you're
writing an article or producing a
podcast, AI is now part of the process.
Number one, the rise of brain computer
interfaces. And here it is, the wildest
one. Brain computer interfaces or BCIs
are starting to move from the lab to the
real world. In early 2024, Neurolink
confirmed it had implanted its first
chip in a human, allowing them to
control a computer cursor just by
thinking. Meanwhile, companies like
Synchron and Precision Neuroscience are
developing less invasive devices that
can restore mobility or communication
for people with paralysis. In clinical
trials, stroke patients have used BCIS
to regain control of limbs or send
messages through thought. We're still in
early days, but the implications are
massive, and they're no longer
theoretical. That wraps the full
countdown. 17 gamechanging trends that
aren't coming someday, they're unfolding
right now. If you've made it this far,
let us know what you think in the
comment section below. For more
interesting topics, make sure to watch
the recommended video that you see on
the screen right now. Thanks for
watching.